议长先生
Mr. Speaker
美利坚合众国总统
the President of the United States
谢谢
Thank you!
我们在创造历史 我们是第一个女性总统 对吗?
We're making history. We're thefirst woman president, right?
我是 你不是 Michael
Well, I am. You're not, Michael.
我是 你弄疼我的手了 你好
I am. Ow, you're hurting my hand. Hi.
我看到你了
Oh, I see you.
"Gettin' Jiggy wit It" Will Smith的一首單曲
谢谢你 我太激动了
Thank you. Well, I'm getting jiggy with it.
我会把那本Philip Roth的书还给你
I'm gonna get that Philip Roth book back to you.
我没有忘
I haven't forgotten about it.
天呐 我都听不到自己了
God, I can't even hear myself.
我在说话吗? 我自己很难听见自己
Am I talking? It's hard for me to hear me.
谢谢你 议长先生
Thank you, Mr. Speaker,
副总统先生
Mr. Vice President,
各位国会议员
members of Congress,
我的美国同胞们
my fellow Americans.
今天我首先...
I'd like to begin today...
想说几句话
by saying a few words.
演讲里最好有些内容
You know, some content would be nice in this speech.
这些只是噪音一样的屁话
This is just noise-shaped air.
我知道 而且她明天将会
I know, and she's reading it tomorrow
在观众面前大声朗读这玩意
out loud in front of an audience.
老大 你还在榨果汁?
Hi, boss. You're still juicing?
- 是的 - Mike想健康一点
- Yeah. - Mike trying to be healthy.
就像土豆试图吹口哨
It's like a potato trying to whistle.
Wendy和我说好了
Wendy and I made a deal.
如果能坚持到50岁 我就再也不用吃水果
If I make it to 50, I can quit fruit for good.
你觉得昨天的草稿怎么样?
What did you think of the draft from last night?
总统说这个演讲太含糊了
POTUS says the speech is too vague.
我以为她希望含糊一点
I thought she wanted it vague.
我猜我们好的过头了
I guess we did too good a job.
所以我们还是不知道
So we still don't know
她在联席会议上的演讲要说些什么
what's going in her speech to the joint session.
我们要怎么办? 像搜索伴郎演讲一样谷歌这个么?
I mean, what do we do? Google it like a best man speech?
别急 船到桥头自然直
Relax, it'll come together.
我做通讯主管的
It always has with every president
每个总统都能搞定
I've been comm director for.
- 一共几个? - 这是第二个
- How many is that? - This would be my second.
实际上 Hughes总统在位时
And actually, it didn't always come together
并不是总能顺利搞定
with President Hughes.
我们失败过很多次
We had many failures.
我想我都习惯了
I guess I just got used to it.
太鼓舞人心了 老兄
Great pep talk, man.
夫人 Ben会将Amy的直邮计划
Ma'am, Ben is getting Amy's direct mail plans
拿给您批准
for you to approve
然后您将接受Ann James宣誓就职住房与城市发展部部长
then you meet the Attorney General re Chicago
之后会见芝加哥检察长
after you swear in Ann James as Housing Sec.
好的
Yep.
您有五个优先通话正在等待
You have five priority calls in a holding pattern,
您可以在摩尔多瓦和皮肤癌之间接听
which can happen between Moldova and skin cancer.
好的
Okay.
然后您可能能休息15分钟
And then you have a potential 15-minute break.
好的 期间我可以睡觉
All right, during which I can sleep
你把营养膏挤到我嘴里
and you can squeeze nutrient paste into my mouth.
别指望了 夫人
Don't count on it, ma'am.
刚才参加演习的美国战舰
US warship on exercises just collided
与希腊渔船相撞
with a Greek fishing boat.
两人死亡 夫人
Two fatalities, ma'am.
是的 将会有场盛大的希腊葬礼
Yeah, we're looking at a big, fat Greek funeral.
我将安排您发表声明 夫人
I'll arrange for you to make a statement, ma'am.
好的 因为我是总统了 看到没?
Yeah, 'cause I'm the president, see?
现在所有事都是我的错
Everything's my fault now.
我有时间与Jim、Dan和Mike谈话吗?
Hey, do I have time to talk to Jim and Dan and Mike?
- 没有 - 我想和他们谈话
- Uh, no, you don't. - I want to.
- 那您就可以 - 好的
- Then you can. - Right.
开场很好 关于Hughes
The opening's good... the stuff about Hughes
和第一夫人的东西 A部分
and FLOTUS, section A.
没有A 我们现在用数字编号
There isn't an A. We're numbering the sections.
- 是吗? -是的 我们都同意用数字
- We are? - We are. We agreed on numbers.
所以A部分现在是第一部分
So section A is now section one.
哈佛教育的好啊
Harvard education right there.
那是谁?
Hey, who is that?
我想是Chloe或者Ellie
Oh, I want to say Chloe or Ellie.
Alyy 不 Sally
Ally. No, Sally
这里有一万个年轻女人
There are a million young women around here
在我看来全都一模一样
and they all look exactly the same to me.
你这个十足的女性歧视者
You big lady racist.
各位 我有个主意
Hey, guys, I had an idea.
这里闻起来像波多黎各
Smells like Puerto Rico in here.
我在榨果汁
I'm juicing.
好吧
Oh, okay.
这个主意怎么样?
So how about this idea?
如果我们把Hughes总统
How about if we take the cut section
草案的削减部分
of the President Hughes draft
和我的“家庭第一”草案的增加开支部分
and we put it together with the spendy section
放在一起 怎么样?
of my Families First draft, right?
再加上母乳喂养的事
Plus with the breast-feeding business.
是 夫人
Yes, ma'am.
那是Mike11A1和Mike11A11文件
That's files Mike11A1 and Mike11A11.
- 那是我的编号 - 好的
- That's for my reference. - Okay.
夫人 他们还没发现三个失踪的登山者
Ma'am, they still haven't found the three missing hikers.
- Cathy会告诉您最新消息 - 哦 谢谢
- Cathy will keep you updated. - Oh, thank you.
- 那是谁? - Cathy是谁?
- Who is that? - Hey, who is Cathy?
我得走了
I've got to go.
好的 走吧
All right, come on.
那就是真正的美国总统
That was the actual President of the United States.
永远这么酷
It never stops being cool.
- 她叫我Mike - 那就是你的名字
- She calls me Mike. - That is your name.
当然我们还得谈到Hughes总统
Obviously we're gonna need to talk about President Hughes.
非常感谢 放轻松什么的
You know, thanks a million, take it easy.
但是要短一点
Let's just keep it short, though.
然后就加入我对未来的愿景
And then that's where we put in my vision for the future,
好吗?
okay?
现在先标记上“未来随便吧”
For now, just put a marker that just says "future whatever."
有个情报简报会议
It's just that I've got an intelligence briefing
我得参加 好吗?
that I've got to get to, okay?
我们应该排好优先顺序
Okay, you know what we should do is prioritize.
因为有削减、增加开支...
'Cause there's like the cutty and the spendy...
我同意
I agree.
人渣们
Suckas.
夫人 我不能陪您去这个情报简报会议
Hey, ma'am, I can't go in this intelligence briefing with you.
- 对 - 您需要什么吗?
- Right. - Is there anything that you need?
我有您要的荷兰眼药水
I got those Dutch eyedrops you requested.
不 我不需要你 Gary
No, I don't need you, Gary.
好的 我就觉得得问问 这是您的咖啡
Great. Great. I just thought I'd ask. Here's your coffee.
- 不用 - 好的
- No. - Okay.
夫人
Yeah, um, ma'am,
您考虑过
have you given any thought
让副总统参加这些会议吗?
to the vice president being at these meetings?
我不想让他像我当副总统时
You know, I mean, I wouldn't want him to have
有那些屎一样的经历
the shitty experience that I had as veep.
是的
No.
遗憾的是 总统已经定好要参加这个会议了
Unfortunately, the precedent has been set for this meeting,
所以我不想改变事情...
so I wouldn't want to go change things...
- 现在这种早期阶段不行 - 正是
- Not at this early stage. - Exactly. Right.
总统需要这个包
President needs the bag.
- 是是是 当然 - 她只需要这个包
- Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, sure. - She only needs the bag.
没这么简单 嗨嗨 轻一点
Okay, it's not that simple. Hey, hey, hey, easy.
你拿得不对 你拿得不对
You're holding it wrong. You're holding it wrong.
姑娘们都哭了 皮条客快死了
Ladies be crying, pimps be dying.
Jonah Ryan来了
It's Jonah Ryan.
我就觉得听到一个小女孩的声音
Ah, I thought I heard a little girl's voice.
- 听得没错 - 你好 先生
- I was right. - Hello, sir.
跟我来 现在这里是男人帮了
Come with me. This is a man hang now.
不会再有润肤露和妇炎洁的恶臭了
It doesn't reek of moisturizer and vaginal spray anymore.
那还只是Dan的味道而已
And that was just Dan.
大个子 你这傻吊还好吗?
Hey, big guy. How's it hanging?
挺好 就像假丁日来到了色情地牢...
You know, pretty good. Like a strap-on in a porn dungeon...
坚如磐石 满是蜜汁
rock hard and coveredin pussy juice.
你喜欢吗? 我有一大堆黄段子
You like that? I got a ton of them.
- 再问我一次 - 嗨 你这傻吊还好吗?
- You can ask me again. - Hey, how's it hanging?
- 像个粗大的肉棍... - Ryan先生
- Like a fat meat fence post... - Mr. Ryan.
哦 副总统先生 您好
Oh, Mr. Vice President. Hello.
感谢您让我过来
Thank you for asking me to stop by.
你知道是谁打赢了战争吗?
You know who won the war?
我相信是... 我们?
I believe that we... we did?
不 不是前线的部队
No, not the grunts in the front.
是幕后的人们
It was the fellas behind the scenes.
情报人员 解密人员
- The intel gatherers, the code crackers.
是的
- Ah, yeah.
我要你做我在西翼的窃听器
I need you to be my West Wing wiretap.
我要你为我刺探情报
I need you to spy for me.
- 是的 先生 - Selina冷藏你了 老古董?
- Yes, sir. - Selina freezing you out, old-timer?
绝对的 虐待循环继续进行
Oh, absolutely. Cycle of abuse continues.
就像天主教堂
Like the Catholic Church.
暗指教堂娈童,男孩们长大了又继续娈童
是的 或者阿肯色州的婚礼
Yeah, or an Arkansas wedding.
阿肯色州施行契约婚姻,结婚麻烦离婚也麻烦.无过错不得离婚
弯腰 击掌
Oh, boom. Lean down, high five.
- 好啊 - 好的
- All right. - Yeah.
就这些 谢谢你 Jonah
That's it, Jonah. Thank you.
是的 先生 谢谢您 先生
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
他是个好孩子
Yeah, he's a good kid.
失陪一下
Yeah, excuse me a second.
所以 你讨厌我 是吗?
So, you hate me, right?
- 什么?- 不不 开玩笑呢 我们是兄弟
- I'm sorry? - No, no, I'm kidding. We're buds.
但我是副总统的幕僚长
But I'm the vice president's chief of staff.
你跑来直接见他
You know, you came to see him directly,
我都不知道你要来
I didn't know you were coming.
- 所以... - 很抱歉 我不是想...
- So... - Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't mean to...
不是... 我不是想越级
not... I didn't mean to step out of line.
不 我们没事 我们是永远的朋友
Oh, no, we're good. We're friends forever.
好的 太好了 谢谢 Teddy
- All right, okay, cool. Thanks, Teddy.
你是个好人 Jonah
- You're a good man, Jonah.
我们需要你这样的人 因为这个游戏需要勇气
We need guys like you, because this game takes guts.
- 是的 是的 - 而且需要有种
- Yeah. Yeah. - Right? And it takes balls.
你都有 朋友
You've got 'em, buddy.
电梯到了
Yeah, elevator's here.
副总统喜欢你
Yeah. The vice president likes you.
我很高兴他喜欢别人
I like when he likes people.
下次来之前给我发短信
So just text me before you come over.
我都会让你进的
I'll always let you in.
- 好的 - 很高兴和你聊天
- Okay. - It was great talking to you.
我不想和Hughes的计划绑在一起
I don't want to be stuck with the Hughes plan.
一个死人的计划
Some dead guy's plan.
他还没死 夫人
Well, he's not dead, ma'am.
没 只是说起来很好玩
No. It's fun for me to say, though.
“家庭第一”的最新民意调查
What are the numbers here
数据怎么样?
in the latest polling on Families First, huh?
抚养孩子脱离贫困 帮助有工作的妈妈?
Raising kids out of poverty and helping working moms?
是的
Yeah.
因为某些原因 贫困的有工作的妈妈喜欢它
Poor working moms seem to love it for some reason.
但是她们只会通过手机投票
But they only ever vote with their phones,
通常是投给其他不会唱歌的贫困年轻妈妈
usually for other poor young moms who can't sing.
好吧 谢谢你们的数据 伙计们
All right, well, thank you for these numbers, guys.
- 谢谢你们 - 不用谢 总统女士
- Thank you. - You're welcome, Madam President.
但是 一定会有什么办法
But, I mean, there has got to be a way
能够完成削减 也能通过“家庭第一”提案
to have the cuts and have the Families First bill.
军队怎么样?
What about the military?
你们认为他们会支持更多的削减吗 ?
Would they go for more cuts, you think?
是的 我们只要弄个丁丁-拇指
Yeah, we just got to do a cock-thumb.
什么? 你说什么?丁丁-拇指?
What? What did you say? A cock-thumb?
- 是的 - 那是啥?
- Yeah. - What is that?
说就行了不要做给我看
Tell me, do not show me.
我们提出一个激进的军队削减提案...
Well, we propose a radical cut to the military...
切掉丁丁...
cutting off the cock...
参谋长联席会议反过来提出
the Joint Chiefs in turn propose
他们自己的更合理的削减...
their own more reasonable cut...
切掉拇指
cutting off the thumb.
也就是众所周知的讨价还价?
Commonly known as negotiating?
好吧 让我们丁丁-拇指
Okay, well, let's cock-thumb.
非常不喜欢这个词
I really don't care for that term.
- 总统夫人 - 嗯?
- Madam President. - Yeah?
印度总理寄给您这个
The Prime Minister of India has sent you this.
- 为什么? - 我没搞明白
- Why? - I can't really work it out,
但是我会安排时间让您感谢他
but I'll put in a time for you to thank him.
不 我不想放在那
No, I don't want that.
- 不要鸭子? - 不要
- No duck? - No.
鸭子去死吧
It's a dead duck.
总统夫人 会找到办法
Madam President, there will be a way
同时做到削减和增加开支
to do both of these things, cuts and spending.
我知道 你绝对可以同时做两个矛盾的事情
I know, you can absolutely do two contradictory things at once.
比如 我爱我母亲
For example, I love my mother,
但是我不得不送她去养老院
but I had to put her in a home.
而且如果我不去看她 其实对她更好
And it's actually better for her if I don't visit.
夫人 这项工作不会简单
Ma'am, this job will never be easy.
我还不知道 天呐
Man, don't I know it. Oh, my God.
我感觉我脑袋里有个仓鼠轮
I feel like I've got a hamster wheel in my head.
你知道那种感觉吗?
You know that feeling?
是的 您听说过那个理论 里根雇了欣克利（曾刺杀里根未遂）
Yeah. Did you ever hear the theory that Reagan hired Hinckley
以便能够在床上躺两周吗?
just so he could get two weeks in bed?
是的 我是信了
Yeah, I'd buy that.
好吧 我们要对参谋长联席会议“丁丁-拇指”
All right, so we'll cock-thumb the Joint Chiefs.
你觉得他们会如何提议?
What do you think they're gonna offer?
不知道 二三十亿吧
I don't know. Two, three billion.
也许卖掉一个没用的机场
You know, maybe sell off a useless airfield.
也许我们可以把阿富汗挂eBay上
Maybe we can put Afghanistan on eBay.
- 能卖个十块钱 - 是的 是的
- Get about 10 bucks for that. - Yeah. Yeah.
Louis 宾州的数据
Louis, Pennsylvania numbers,
竞选办公室 马里兰
我要最新数据和两天前的数据 快搞定
I need them up to date and two days ago, so work it out.
我有缺席选票和提前投票的最新数据
I have the new figures on absentee ballots and early voting.
很好 坐直升机把它放到
Great, take a chopper up and add it to the
我桌上那一大堆顶上去
top of the pile on my desk.
Cafferty先生想了解直邮广告计划
Mr. Cafferty wants to know our direct mail plans.
总统需要做决定
The president needs to make a decision.
削减或者在“家庭”提案上增加开支
Cuts or spending on the Families bill.
- 明白了 - 先有鸡先有蛋的情况
- Got it. - Chicken and egg scenario.
是的 但是这里的母鸡拒绝下蛋
Yeah, but where the chicken is just refusing to ovulate.
演讲里说什么?
What's in the speech?
总统要削减赤字还是在“家庭”上增加开支?
Will the president cut the deficit or spend on families?
财政紧缩还是建游乐场?
Austerity or playgrounds?
（要为集会订乐队吗?）
她还在考虑各种可能
She's considering her options.
或者她根本没头绪
Or she doesn't have a clue.
我们承担不了落在后面
We cannot afford to fall behind.
我们和Chung难分高下
We're neck and neck with Chung.
你听说Thornhill的传言吗?
And have you heard the Thornhill rumor?
我当然知道 Amy
Of course I have, Amy.
我是白宫新闻秘书
I'm the White House Press Secretary.
但是假设我不知道
But imagine I haven't.
他可能会退出
He might quit.
（Thornhill的竞选经理希望...）
不再跟Selina竞争提名
Stop running against Selina for the nomination.
我的助理通过提示卡告诉我
And my assistant tells me via cue card
（...会面 不好意思翻页了）
Ericsson想会面
that Ericsson wants a meeting.
Thornhill退出太好了
Thornhill quitting is good.
不 等等 你... 不不 很好
No, wait, you're... no, no, it's good.
不 如果他弃牌 Chung会得到他的选票
No. If he folds, Chung gets his votes.
候选人扑克
Candidate poker.
别怪我 Amy
Well, don't blame me for this, Amy.
不杀来使
Don't shoot the messenger.
是我刚告诉你这个消息
I just gave you the message.
是你被来使杀了
You're being shot by the messenger.
（另外 Mike McLintock也想和您通话）
那也不好
Well, it's still not good.
这个演讲里还是没有内容
There's still no content in this speech.
- 就像牛肉面不加牛肉 - 我知道 我知道
- It's like a diet soufflee. - I know, I know.
Sue 总统今天下午有空闲时间
Sue, does the president have any spare time
再来一次讲演稿讨论会吗
this afternoon for an extra speechwriting meeting?
老鼠能飞吗 Mike?
Can mice levitate, Mike?
它们能边飞边从眼里发射激光吗?
Can they levitate and fire lasers out of their mouse eyes?
不能
No.
那么我们刚刚都问了
Well, then we've just asked each
一个同样荒谬的问题
other equally ridiculous questions.
这个包还给我的时候 跟我想的不一样
Hey, this bag was not returned to me in the condition I expected.
很多盖子都松了 你知道...
There was a lot of loose lids. Do you know...
一切都变了 是吗老兄?
A lot of changes, huh, buddy?
是啊
Yeah.
好吧 说的具体的措辞...
All right, so look, in terms of actual words...
大部分会议我都没有安全级别
I mean, most meetings I don't even have security clearance for.
海军勤务员给她送喝的
Navy stewards bring her drinks in.
我几乎见不到她
I barely see her.
你可以用第一夫人的窗口
You can just use the FLOTUS window.
向下就能看到椭圆形办公室
Looks right down onto the Oval Office.
- 是吗? - 当然
- You can? - Sure.
许多焦虑的第一夫人都用过
A lot of anxious First Ladies use it.
好吧 不跟你计较这个 多谢关心
Okay, that's ignored, but thank you for your concern.
Mike 你都应付不来了
Mike, you can barely cope.
你对新定位感觉怎么样?
How are you finding the new setup?
实际上 我现在算是出名了
I'm actually kind of famous now.
真的么? 你确定?
Really? You sure about that?
是的 我今天在街上被认出来了
Yeah, I got recognized on the street today.
那家伙其实见过我 但是忘记了
Guy had already met me and then forgot that he met me
然后又从电视上认出了我
and then recognized me from TV
然后又记起我了
and then remembered me again.
真是个美妙的故事 Mike
That's a great story, Mike.
如果你们这群小母狗需要
Oh, hey, if any of you new bitch puppies need help
帮忙找妈妈的奶头
finding the mommy teats around here,
去问西翼的兽医 好吗?
you can just ask a West Wing vet, 'kay?
新副总统办公室怎么样?
Oh, how's the new veep's office?
- 什么? - 新副总统办公室
- What? - The new veep's office.
棒极了 你还要问?
It's great. Why are you even asking?
太好了 真他妈的棒极了
I mean, it's so good. It's fucking... it's great.
我 Doyle
Me, Doyle.
还有 Teddy 当然 Teddy
I mean, come on, Teddy. Of course, Teddy.
那边太好了 伙计们 太好了
So good over there, guys. So good.
很高兴见到你 Ericsson先生
It's my pleasure to meet you, Mr. Ericsson.
很好
Good.
房间不错
It's a nice room.
适合孤独的自杀或者和秘书偷情
For a lonely suicide or an affair with your secretary.
我们要谨慎 这里没有华府的人
It's discreet. There's no DC people here.
我用Lazlo Whittaker这个名字预订的
I booked it using the name Lazlo Whittaker.
"弗拉基米尔(普金名).求关注"这个名字被占了?
Was Vladimir Draw-Attention-To-Myself already taken?
要咖啡吗?
A coffee?
- 无脂拿铁 - 特浓美式咖啡
- Skinny latte. - Americano triple shot.
要配餐吗? 三明治?
How about any sides? Maybe a sandwich?
我要一个蛋白质棒 我对夏威夷果过敏
I'll take a protein bar. I'm allergic to macadamia nuts.
明白... Ericsson先生不要致死的夏威夷果
Got it... no deadly macadamias for Mr. Ericsson.
杏仁羊角包 苏打水
- Almond croissant, sparkling water.
我也要水
- I'll take a water, too.
我得拿笔纸笔
You know what? Just gonna grab a pen and paper.
我得记下来
Let me write this down.
或者我就用脑子记下来
Or I will remember it using my brain.
我脑子不错
I've got a pretty good one.
伊利诺伊理工学院毕业的
Illinois Institute of Technology.
我就有话直说了
I'll cut right to the chase.
太好了 因为刚才那一分钟真是非常漫长
Good, 'cause that last minute was a very long minute.
- Joe要... - Joe Thornhill要退出吗?
- Is Joe... - Joe Thornhill quitting?
好问题 我正要问呢
Nice question. I was just asking it.
Joe没要退出 但是传言有一半是对的
Joe's not quitting, but the rumor's half right.
我刚辞去了他的竞选经理一职
I've just quit as his campaign manager.
你他妈的为啥要那样做?
Why would you do that the fuck for?
摇摆Joe(著名棒球手 戏称)已经触顶要走下坡路了
Joltin' Joe has hit the top of his bounce.
他自己意识到了还是要看ESPN(体育电视台)才知道?
Does he realize that or is he gonna find out on ESPN?
不 他非常非常傻逼
No, he's very, very stupid.
我原本以为他会是个有趣的挑战
I thought he'd be an interesting challenge,
结果只是无聊的苦差事
but he's a boring chore.
你的工作非常有趣
Your job is very interesting.
- 好吧... - 很具挑战
- Well... - Challenging.
非常令人兴奋的工作
Very exciting job.
我的工作 是的 确实
My job, yes, it is.
我拥有的工作 是非常好的工作
The job I have is a very good job.
- Gary - Sue 怎么样?
- Gary. - Hey, Sue, how's it going?
- 我刚到这儿 - 我明白 Gary
- I was just in here. - I get it, Gary.
- 你真漂亮 - 你不用装
- You look pretty. - You don't need to pretend.
我只想知道
All I need to know is
她桌上的黑色文件夹有没有被移动
has the black binder from her desk been moved?
- 黑色文件夹 是的 是的 - 好的
- The black binder? Yeah, yeah, it has. - Okay.
你知道吗? 我从没有从这个角度看过她
Do you know what? I have never looked at her from this angle.
而她还是一如既往的闪耀... 好吧
And she still just radiates... okay.
你认为Selina会赢吗?
Do you think Selina will win?
艰苦的战斗 不过她能赢
Tough fight, but she can win.
你说她能赢 我问她会不会赢
You said she can win. I asked if she will win.
抱歉 你是要苏打水还是纯净水?
I'm sorry, was that sparkling or still water?
还有什么可颂? 我绝对记得其他的
And what kind of croissant? I definitely remember the rest.
好吧 我要离开这个房间了
Okay, I'm leaving this hotel room.
再见 Amy 再见 Lazlo
Good-bye, Amy. Good-bye, Lazlo.
他刚辞去了Thornhill的竞选经理一职
He just quit being Thornhill's campaign manager.
不知道他下一步要干嘛
Wonder what he'll do next.
他是美国最好的竞选经理
He's the best campaign manager in America.
- 之一 - 他想要什么工作都能得到
- One of them. - I mean, he could have any job he wants.
- 是的 - 他能干你的工作
- Yeah. - He could have your job.
我大声说出来了
You know, I'm saying all this out loud and
真不应该
I probably shouldn't be.
谢谢 夫人 您要我带走黑色文件夹里
Thanks, ma'am. Would you like me to take away
签过的信件吗?
the signed letters in the black binder?
你怎么知道我签过了?
How'd you know I signed those?
我有第六感
Oh, I have a sixth sense.
需要的时候还有第七感
And a seventh for when I need it.
- Gary.- 在在在
- Gary. - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- 你有我的护手霜吗? - 是的
- Do you have my hand cream? - Oh, yeah.
- 我有La Prairie的新产品... - 不不
- I got the new formula from La Prairie... - No, no.
把整管都给我
Just give me the whole tube
下一个会议你也不能参加
'cause you can't come into this next meeting either.
我完全不在意的 你知道
And I'm totally fine with that, you know.
参谋长联席会议马上到
Well, Joint Chiefs are on their way.
我们随时将听到他们的蛋蛋叮呤当啷作响
We should hear their big clanking balls any second.
然后墙上的画都震掉下来
And then all the paintings will fall off the walls.
- Gare? - 在在
- Oh, hey, Gare? - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
海军勤务员送的什么咖啡?
What is the coffee that the navy stewards use?
我都不敢想
I can only imagine.
- 升天了 - 哦
- It's heaven. - Oh.
简直像哥伦比亚式舌尖上的性爱
It's like Colombian tongue sex.
为什么我们不喝那种咖啡?
Why don't we ever use that coffee?
不知道 但是你喜欢我们以前的咖啡
I don't know, but you love our old coffee.
- 不喜欢 - 好吧
- Nah. - No.
- (电影) - 什么?
- "Reservoir Dogs," huh? - Excuse me?
我从来没看过 但是我知道
I've never actually seen it, but as I understand,
那里有一幕他们就像这样走一列
there's a scene where they all walk in a row like this.
你认为他们会提议什么?
What do you think they're gonna offer us?
二十亿 三十 最多
Uh, $2 billion. Three, tops.
你准备好面对这些板寸蠢货了没?
So you ready for these buzz-cut bozos?
你说什么呢?
What are you talking about?
我已经习惯对付愤怒 好斗
I'm used to dealing with angry, aggressive,
功能失调的男人 也就是所有男人
dysfunctional men, i.e., men.
那是我们最擅长的
Well, that's what we do best.
除了那个 还是初次圣餐时放屁
That and farting during first Communions.
真有趣... 我都不怎么把你当男人
It's funny... I don't really think of you as a man.
- 好吧 - 他们来了
- Oh. Okay. - Oh, here they are.
夫人 参谋长联席会议
Ma'am. Joint Chiefs of Staff.
- 先生们 - 总统女士
- Gentlemen. - DMadam President.
请进 请坐
Please come in. Take a seat.
我知道你们正在准备战斗 我明白
I understand you're on the warpath. I get that.
我想那是你们最喜欢的事
I think it's your favorite path.
- 吸血鬼! - 老天 别!
- Vampires! - God, stop!
如果我是忍者 你现在已经死了
If I was a ninja, you'd be dead right now.
Obi-Wan Kenobi 星球大战里的绝地武士 Jonah在前面加上J 和自己名字混合
这是绝地大师的生存课程
That's a life lesson courtesy of Jobi-Wan Kenobi.
- 不好玩 老兄 - 你干嘛呢?
- That's not cool, man. - Wait, what are you even doing?
看着总统
I'm keeping an eye on the president.
去隔壁的藏书处
Are you sure you wouldn't be more comfortable
不是更舒服吗
at the book depository next door?
- 请你离开好吗? - 开玩笑呢
- Can you just leave, please? - It was a joke.
你知道VP办公室的Teddy Sykes吗?
Hey, do you know Teddy Sykes over in the VP's office?
Teddy? 知道 他是个好人
Teddy? Yeah. He's a great guy.
- 是吗? - 他很爱 很爱亲力亲为(动手动脚)
- He is? - He's really, really hands-on.
好的
Oh. Okay.
你为什么打听Teddy?
Why do you want to know about Teddy?
他开了个玩笑 很好笑
He played this joke, and, I mean, it was really funny,
但是 不知道 有一点奇怪...
but, I don't know, it was a little weird and...
总统在干什么?
what's the president doing?
看起来她正在会见参谋长联席会议
It looks like she's having a meeting with the Joint Chiefs.
我想不是预先安排的
I don't think it's scheduled.
我们知道您需要削减 但是现役军队中
We know you need cuts, but a further 25,000 reduction
再减少两万五千个职位 完全难以想象
in active military troop is unthinkable.
是的 但是我在这儿呢 我正想着呢
Yeah, but here I am. I'm thinking it.
唯一无法想象的事情只有有些事是无法想象的
The only unthinkable thing is that anything is unthinkable.
Kent幸运饼干箴言大师
Kent majored in fortune cookies.
哦哦! 天呐!
Oh! Oh! Oh, my God!
你没事吧? 你看起来... 看起来没事
Are you okay? You look... you look okay.
你的前任说过 四十二万军队
Your predecessor said that a force of 420,000
已经绰绰有余...
would be more than adequate...
那是胡扯八道 抱歉 夫人
Yeah, that's horse hockey. Forgive me, ma'am.
不不 无需道歉
No, no. No forgiveness needed.
至少你没说那是他妈的狗屁
I mean, at least you didn't say that's fucking bullshit.
好吧 这就是说
Okay, well, let's see.
- 我们卡在这了 - 我们想提出一个替代的削减计划
- We're stuck. - We'd like to propose an alternative cut.
好的 替代的削减计划
Oh, okay. An alternative cut.
听起来很有趣 是不是 Ben?
That sounds interesting, doesn't it, Ben?
- 非常有趣 - 非常有趣
- Very interesting. - Very interesting.
N620型潜艇没有任务
The N620 submarine lacks a mission.
它设计用于过时的冷战局面
It was designed for an outdated Cold War scenario
已经和传真机录像机一样随风而去了
that's gone the way of the fax machine and the VCR.
好的 估算的话
Okay, so what does that mean
这意味着多少钱?
in terms of numbers ballpark wise?
我是说 如果我们像你建议的一样废除这个计划?
I mean, if we were to scrap this program you suggest?
五百亿
$50 billion.
什... 什么 再说一遍?
I... I'm sorry, could you say that again?
五百亿
50 billion.
五 零 再加上一大串零?
Five-zero followed by a bunch of zeroes?
- 九个零 - 是的
- Nine. - Yes.
好吧 你知道 我想...
All right, well, you know, I think...
你知道 我们需要考虑一下...
well, you know, this gives us something to think about.
第三页 我想是的
It's page three, I think it is.
我想我们可能有些不同...
Yeah. Well, I think we might have different...
我猜灵犬莱西想告诉我们什么
I think Lassie is trying to tell us something.
总统和参谋长联席会议正在开会 现在
POTUS and the Joint Chiefs meeting, happening now.
靠! 他妈的 我告诉过你 Teddy
Oh, shit! God damn it. I told you, Teddy.
先生 我能坐下吗? 我感觉我的隔膜都裂了
Sir, can I sit down? I think I split my diaphragm.
我要你跑去
I need you to run.
- 谢谢您 - 好的
- Thank you. - Okay.
五百亿!
$50 billion!
大师级表现 夫人
That was masterly, ma'am.
- 我的天! - 或者女大师级表现 随便哪个不唐突的词
- Oh, my God! - Or mistressly, whichever isn't offensive.
那不是丁丁-拇指 那是丁丁-丁丁
That wasn't a cock-thumb. That was a cock-cock.
- 是啊 我都快吐了 - 五百亿有多少?
- Yeah, I nearly puked. - How big is $50 billion?
换成五块纸币搬进来
Get it in here in five-dollar bills.
爬到顶我都要被冻伤了
I'm gonna climb it and see if I get frostbite.
哦 Andrew
Oh, oh, Andrew.
- 听说有个会 - 是的
- Heard there was a meeting. - Yes.
只是打扫房间
It was just a little light housecleaning.
- 除尘 真的 - 我一路跑来的
- Dusting, really. - I ran all the way here.
你知道吗? 你身体太棒了
Well, you know what? You're in phenomenal shape.
对于你这个年龄的人来说 真是非同寻常
For a man of your age, it's just extraordinary.
你渴吗? 想喝点什么?
Are you thirsty? Do you want something to drink?
不用 我事情很多
No, I have a lot to do.
好的 拜拜 哦 等等 Andrew
Okay, bye-bye. Oh, wait, Andrew.
你能关下门吗?
Would you close the door behind you?
谢谢 很高兴见到你
Thanks. But nice to see you.
"我们相信美国的劳动者 我们相信美国的创造力"
"We bet on American workers. We bet on American ingenuity."
各位 写的简直妙极了!
Guys, this writing is absolutely fantastic!
这是"五十度棒"
It's "50 Shades of Great."
- 真的 - 谢谢您 总统夫人
- Really. - Thank you, Madam President.
全都是一天的工作 也花了一整夜
All in a day's work that also took all night.
- 我看起来怎么样? - 非常美 非常美
- How do I look? - Oh, beautiful, beautiful.
- 很好 - 让我把这个眼镜拿出来
- Good. - Actually, let me take these glasses out.
- 看起来您好像长鸡鸡了 - 什么?
- It looks like you have a penis. - What?
如果... 如果您要的话 您绝对能长出来
Which you can totally pull off if you had... if you had to.
- 该走了 - 好运 总统夫人
- Got to go. - Good luck, Madam President.
- 再见 - 干得漂亮 各位
- Bye. - Well done, guys.
我不想说脏话 各位
I don't like to swear, guys,
但是我想S马上就要撞到F了
but I think the S is about to hit the F.
屎(shit)马上要撞到操(fuck)了?
The shit is gonna hit the fuck?
不 F是电扇(fan) Mike 不是操 (屎撞扇:麻烦大了)
No, F is for fan, Mike, not fuck.
屎怎么会撞到操? 屎不会撞到操
Why would shit hit fuck? Shit doesn't hit fuck.
我读了这个演讲 我的这些朋友也读了
Well, I've read the speech. So have my friends here.
抱歉 各位 这是军事工业复合体
Oh, sorry. Guys, this is the military industrial complex.
军事工业复合体
Military industrial complex,
这是总统的走狗们
these are the president's flying monkeys.
这是关于潜艇工作吗?
Is this about the submarine jobs?
给冰雪女王Elsa(冰雪奇缘)加他妈十分
10 fucking points to Elsa the ice queen.
要调整下用词吗 Roger?
Shall we recalibrate our language, Roger?
叫我国会议员Furlong 灰发猫王
It's Congressman Furlong to you, gray Elvis.
以及 是的 这正是关于
And, yes, this is about specifically
这个演讲将会搞掉的
1,900 submarine jobs in my district
我选区里的1900个潜艇工作
that this announcement will torpedo.
N620型是为了不存在的威胁设计的
The N620s are for a threat that doesn't exist.
我们还应该搞个抗独角兽战略
We may as well have an anti-unicorn strategy.
而且它们要花费五百亿美元 五百亿
And they cost $50 billion dollors. 50 billion.
我还得再说一遍美元 美元
And I'm gonna say dollars again. Dollars.
你以为整个潜艇都是在同一个地方建造的?
You think the whole sub is made in one place?
因为翅片 或者不知道叫啥的玩意
Because the fin, or whatever the fuck,
来自一个州的一个工厂
it comes from one factory in one state.
而他妈的小圆窗
And then this little round fucking
来自另一个地方
window comes from another place.
懂吗? 而燃料棒来自威斯康星州叫乳酪鸡巴的破地方
All right? And the fuel rods are from Cheesedick, Wisconsin.
我们将会在所有地方失去选票和席位
We are going to lose votes and seats everywhere.
所以把潜望镜从菊花里拔出来
So take the periscope out of your asses
看看马上就要击中你们的弹头
and look at the warhead of shit that's coming at you.
家养小精灵Dobby(哈利波特) 我们听够了
Hey, Dobby the house elf, we've had enough.
- 快走吧 - 好吧
- Just get out. - Okay.
你们可以跟"家庭第一"提案说再见了
You can wave bye-bye to the Families First bill
因为这些选区的议员
because the lawmakers in these districts
将会用瓦肯死亡之握(星际迷航)干死你们
are going to Vulcan death grip you to fuck.
生生不息 滚你妈的(星际迷航)
Live long and fuck off.
演讲已经上提词器了
Speech is already in the teleprompter.
她马上就到 我心脏病要他妈的发作了
She's on her way down. I'm gonna have a fucking heart attack.
你的心脏要开苞见红了 Mike?
Popped your cardiac cherry, huh, Mike?
我要和总统谈谈
I'm gonna go talk to the president.
- 议长先生 - 为您高兴 夫人
- Hey, Mr. Speaker. - Thrilled for you, ma'am.
你在讽刺我呢 Jim
Oh, see, you're being sarcastic, Jim.
绝对为您高兴 真的
Absolutely thrilled, really.
- 看 这就是讽刺 - 喜不自胜
- Oh, no, see, that's sarcasm. - Couldn't be more thrilled.
- 就是讽刺 - 不 不是
- That is sarcasm. - No, it's not.
- 就是 我听出来了 还有... - 夫人
- It is, I see it. Yeah, and... oh. - Ma'am.
你好 Ben
Hi, Ben.
你这脸跟探长狗(动画片)一样是怎么了?
What's with that Deputy Dawg face you got going?
有很多选区不会支持潜艇削减
Well, there's a lot of districts that won't support the submarine cuts.
所以如果您提出 他们会杀...
So if you go ahead, they're gonna kill...
他们就会搞死我的"家庭第一"?
They're gonna kill my Families First, then?
这是它操蛋的本意
That's the long and shit of it.
好吧 我们要从其他地方搞钱
Okay. We're gonna have to find the money somewhere else.
好吗? 让高中生初三就毕业什么的
Okay? Just end high school in ninth grade or something.
从演讲里去掉潜艇削减
Just take the submarine cuts out of the speech.
好的
Okay.
- 去改 快点 - 是
- Change it. Hurry up. - Yeah.
议长先生
Mr. Speaker,
美国总统
the President of the United States.
她上台了
She's onstage.
好的 好的 我们中的一个要写一些新内容
Okay, okay, one of us needs to write some new text
而我真的要缓口气
and I really need to stop shallow breathing.
总统说话了 我们要剪掉削减部分
POTUS has spoken. We cut the cuts.
好的 Sue 我们要找到演讲的那部分
Okay, Sue, we need to go to that section of the speech.
我觉得没法在Selina看演讲前部的时候
I don't think I can edit that section
修改那一部分
and still have Selina see the top of the speech.
- 让我看看 这么做会怎样... - 会这样
- Let me see what happens if I... - That's what happens.
我们是第一个女性总统
We're the first woman president.
我是 你不是 Michael
Right? Well, I am. You're not, Michael.
- 恭喜 夫人 - 我看着你
- Congratulations, ma'am. - I'm looking at you,
但是我在和别人握手
but I'm shaking somebody else's hand.
感觉好奇怪
It's the strangest feeling.
哦 是你啊 就是你 对吗?
Oh, it's you. That is you, right?
是他
It's him.
快点! 你为什么只用两个指头打字?
Hurry up! How come you type with only two fingers?
你又不是树獭
- You're not a sloth.
等等 她有纸质版 对吗?
- No, wait, she's got the hard copy, right?
那是她的后备降落伞
I mean, that's her backup chute right there.
太好了 我们修改这个的时候 她读那个
Great, she reads that while we edit this.
- 好的 好的 - 我拿了她的眼镜
- Okay. Okay. - I have her glasses.
- 什么? - 我拿了她的眼镜
- What? - I've got her glasses.
你不应该拿
You should not have those.
你为什么要把总统弄瞎 Gary?
Why have you blinded the president, Gary?
它破坏了她裙子的线条...
They were ruining the line of her dress and...
- Walsh先生 - 没人比我更恨我自己了
- Mr. Walsh. - No one hates me more than I hate myself.
你搞砸了 快跑去礼堂
You're wrong there. You run into the chamber
给她送眼镜
and you give her the glasses
然后继续跑一直跳到海里
and you keep running until you hit the ocean.
快去 Gary 礼堂 现在
Go, Gary. Chamber, now.
太晚了 她已经上讲台了
Too late, she's already at the podium.
我杀了她 我杀了她
Well, I've killed her. I've killed her, okay?
谢谢 议长先生...
Thank you, Mr. Speaker...
- 天啊 天啊 天啊 - 副总统先生
- God, God, God. - Mr. Vice President,
各位议员 我的美国同胞们
members of Congress, my fellow Americans.
今天我首先...
I'd like to begin today...
想说几句话
by saying a few words.
我想请大家花一点时间
I'd like to ask for some time to think
缅怀Hughes总统
about President Hughes
和前任第一夫人
and the former First Lady.
让我们... 我们花几分钟低下头
So let's... let's take a moment to bow our heads
怀念他们对这个伟大国家的贡献
and remember their contribution to this great nation.
他们还没死
They're not dead.
哈哈哈! 我搞定了! 我太牛逼了
Ha ha ha! I've done it! I rule so hard.
别停 给我U盘
Don't stop. Give me the USB.
妈的 我总是搞错
Oh, shit. I always get it wrong.
这是一半一半的机会 我从来没搞对过
It's a 50-50 chance. I never get the right side up.
上帝保佑他们 多好的人 多好的人
God bless them. What people, what people.
确确实实 没有语言 可以表达
There are literally no words.
快点 快点
Come on, come on. Hurry up.
人民想要知道我是谁
People want to know who I am
而我想告诉他们太多
and I want to tell them so much.
上线了 鹰眼已经注意到了
It is up and the eagle has noticed.
我的整个职业生涯刚才都从眼前闪过
My entire career just flashed before my eyes.
真是难以置信
It was incredibly impressive.
它的政府可靠的手中
That its government was in safe hands.
不 那是错的措辞...
No, that's...that's the wrong phrase.
嗯? 什么?
我想我把新东西
I think I put the new stuff
放在了Mike11A1 而不是Mike11A1A
in Mike11A1, not Mike11A1A.
也可能是反过来
But that could be the other way around.
这个版本还有占位符在里面
This version still has placeholders in it
下一部分只有"未来随便吧"
and the next section just says "future whatever."
所以今天我不想只谈现在
So today I don't just want to talk about the present.
我想说一说未来
I want to talk about the future.
无论什么将会发生...
Whatever we have in store...
我们都无法预知
cannot be known.
但是随着时间... 我们会知道
But given time, it... it can be understood.
过去也曾是未来
The past was once the future.
我要说 未来是未知的
The future is, I should say, unknown.
事实上 是不可知的
It is in fact unknowable.
她在唱爵士一样即兴创作
She's bebop speaking.
所以我邀请你们与我在站台见
So I'm asking you to meet me at the station
与我一起登上一列
and join me as we board a train
通往未来的列车
bound for a place called the future.
我讨厌爵士乐 但是这确实令人印象深刻
I detest jazz, but this is impressive.
而无论那个未来怎样 我们都已经准备好了
And we will be ready for that future whatever.
我快哭了 我都不知道我还能几乎能哭
I'm almost crying. I didn't know I could still almost do that.
但是现在... 但现在是时候拉远未来
But now... but now it's time to roll past the future
非常非常快地继续前进
to move on and do so very, very quickly.
当我们想到未来 我们想到孩子
When we think of what is to come, we think of our children.
哈哈 太棒了! 我们进入正轨了
Ha ha, superb! We're back on track.
演讲的剩下部分都没问题？
And the rest of the speech is okay?
- 是的 绝对的 - 好的 谢谢
- Yes. Absolutely. - Okay, thank you.
呃...不是
Uh... uh, no.
而当我们想到我们的孩子...
And when we think of our children...
我想这个版本还包含
I think this version still has
Hughes总统的老的增加开支计划
President Hughes' old spending plan in it.
我们将要投资六百亿美元
We will invest $60 billion dollors
建设新的N620型潜艇
in the new N620 submarine fleet.
该死
God damn it.
对这个至关重要的现代化防御系统
That's a further $10 billion-dollor-investment
增加一百亿美元投资
in this vital and modern defense system.
她刚宣布了一个死人的计划
Well, she just announced a dead guy's plan.
他还没他妈的死呢
He's not fucking dead.
你觉得她注意到了吗?
Do you think she noticed?
我想是的 Mike
I think so, Mike.
我他喵的读的是个什么鬼?
What the hell was I reading?
你们应该把潜艇削减去掉
You were supposed to take the submarine cuts out,
不是在它们身上多花一百亿
not spend an extra 10 billion on them.
现在 给我... Gary?
Now, give... Gary?
眼镜
Glasses.
好的
Yep.
我说 这个演讲
I mean, this speech
本来应该完美地定义我的任期
was supposed to perfectly define my presidency.
修一下好吗?
Okay, you want to fix these?
许多城市的孩子
Whole cities of children
本来可以免于贫困
were going to be saved from poverty.
现在不然 这些钱
Instead now, that money
将会用于建造过时的
is going to fund obsolete,
金属的 巨大的 假丁日
metal, giant dildos.
你们知道不知道...
Do you have any idea what...
你们离我越远越好
You need to be far away from me.
滚出我的办公室
Get out of my office.
夫人 我知道您现在现在需要独处
Ma'am, I know you need to be alone right now.
只是这些签过的...
It's just that these sign-offs...
我就... 我就放在这
I'm just... I'll just leave 'em.
- 是的 - 好的
- Yeah. - Yeah.
抱歉 夫人 您说不想被打扰
Sorry, ma'am, you said not to interrupt,
但是我们有个安排在现在的竞选会议
but we have a campaign meeting scheduled for right now.
- 我知道 Amy - 我出去取消
- I know, Amy. - I'm descheduling as I exit.
总统夫人 我知道您赶我出去
Madam President, I know you kicked me out,
但是我们的无人机刚刚在也门炸错人了
but we just droned the wrong guy's truck in Yemen.
- 谢谢你 Ben - 好的
- Thank you, Ben. - Great.
我去写个报告
Guess I'll write a report.
- 夫人 我修好... - 滚出去!
- Hey, ma'am, I got your... - Get out!
是
Yeah.
总统夫人 抱歉打扰
Madam President. Sorry to interrupt.
想告诉您两个登山者被发现死亡
Just to let you know that two of the hikers are dead.
请你离开好吗?
Could you please leave?
对不起 总统夫人
Sorry, Madam President.
等等 什么登山者?
Wait. What hikers?
什么登山者?!
What hikers?!